Sara Taylor

Lowell, MI 49331

Phone: 616-558-1817 **Email**: sara.swifti@gmail.com **LinkedIn**: https://www.linkedin.com/in/sara-taylor-7a850331/

Summary:

Account Executive • Full Stack Web Developer • Field Sales Account Manager

An Account Executive with twenty years' experience in interdisciplinary business, education, and the sciences. A dependable professional with the ability to troubleshoot complex account and client issues, resulting in mutually agreeable solutions.

Technical Skills

Languages: JavaScript ES6+, CSS3, HTML5, SQL, NoSQL

Applications: GitHub, MongoDB, MySQL

Tools: Express, React, Node, Handlebars, JQuery, Bootstrap, Material-UI

Relevant Experience

Michigan Account Executive, Southwest Michigan Houghton Mifflin Harcourt

April 2019 – October 1st, 2020 Boston, MA

K-12 Educational Program and Content Provider

- Expanded industry influence with analytics planning sessions: Generated \$550,00+ in new intervention program revenue by collaborating with the HMH's Solution Architect Team in overseeing academic gaps-and-gains analytics data meetings, throughout all seasons of the sales cycle.
- Increased personal capacity for content knowledge in a highly competitive industry: Maintained a complete and comprehensive working knowledge of core, supplemental and intervention k-12 programs along with technology functionality for each program.
- Complete working knowledge of all sales motions from start to finish. Fluency with the Salesforce interface by managing a multifaceted pipeline, tracking, and moving opportunities to completed sales motions, account strategizing using data analytics, writing cost proposals while positioning pricing and programs accordingly.
- Position eliminated following market downturn and organizational realignment.

Associate Account Executive, Michigan and Northern Indiana March 2015 – April 2019

Houghton Mifflin Harcourt

Adjacent Markets: Private, Parochial and Charter Schools Division

- Contributing member of the Michigan Private, Parochial and Charter Schools' division by meeting or exceeding our sales quota from 2015 through 2018.
- Partnered with Regional Account Executives in a six (6) state territory with curriculum support, sales calls, program implementations, as well as delivering sales presentations and implementation training both in person and remotely.
- Designated regional sales and implementation professional for Math and World Languages for sales below \$50,000 threshold.

Additional Experience

Per Diem Curriculum Specialist ProUnlimited,

November 2013-March 2015

Servicing Houghton Mifflin Harcourt accounts through a contracted provider

 Assisted Houghton Mifflin Harcourt Area Account Executives with curriculum support, sales calls, and program implementations of Math and World Languages.

Athletes in Action, Senior Staff

1994-2013

Ohio: 1994-1999 California: 1999-2003 Istanbul, Turkey: 2003-2013

Michigan: June 2013- November 2013

- Small group leader and children's program coordinator: Refugee Mothers and Toddlers Food Program, Union Church, Istanbul. 2012-2013.
- **Organizational Leader:** National Language proficiency coordinator, events planning, new staff application evaluator and interviewer, new staff trainer. 2005-2013.
- **Teacher**: International Gateway Academy, Istanbul Turkey 2007-2011.
- **Curriculum Developer:** Turkish language for primary school students. 2010-2011.Program is still being used as of 10/2020.
- **Counselor**: students and small groups at the University of Cincinnati, University of Dayton and University of Southern California, San Bernardino. 1994-2003.

Education

Bootcamp Full-Stack Web Design Certificate MichinState University, May 2021
A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills.

Food Science and Human Nutrition, BS Associates in Science Associates in Arts

Michigan State University Grand Rapids Community College Grand Rapids Community College

Languages

Turkish- Advanced Spanish-Beginner/Intermediate